## YUNUS IBRAHIM

South Portland, ME 04106

Phone: 207 420 6078 | Email: hireme@yunusibrahim.me

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vunus-ibrahim | GitHub: https://github.com/Yunusib12 |

Portfolio: <a href="https://yunusibrahim.me">https://yunusibrahim.me</a>

### SUMMARY

Dedicated and efficient Full Stack Developer with a background in Network and System Administration and educated through the University of New Hampshire Coding Bootcamp. Through developed skills, am able to create an intuitive user experience through responsive web designs. Enjoy learning new skills, collaborating and problem solving.

Fluent in English, French, Swahili, and Kirundi.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

CSS3, HTML5, Materialize, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, React, Angular, VB.Net, PHP, Node.js, Express.js, Apache, Data Modeling, Relational Database (SQL, MySQL, Sequelize), MongoDB, Mongoose, Amazon Web Services, S3 Bucket, GitHub, Heroku, Trello, Asana, Vagrant, Docker, Linux, Systems analysis.

#### **PROJECTS**

### FoodSta | https://github.com/Yunusib12/Foodsta.git | https://deliciousfoodsta.com

- Allows users to search for nearby restaurants, cuisines and meals
- Users can create accounts and post reviews about their meals
- User can use the Authentication and Validation through Passport.JS, the User can save their chart(s) since it is securely held within our MySQL database.
- Tools used: Angular, HTML5/SCSS, AWS S3, Auth0, Express, Sequelize, Node.js, Google Places API
- Type: Full Stack

### Charted | https://github.com/Yunusib12/Charted.git | https://charted-v1-0.herokuapp.com/

- Allows farmers and ranchers struggling to decipher their livestock and / or crop performance
- With Charted, a farmer / rancher can upload a .CSV file for on-demand field management.
- Tools used: JavaScript, Passport.js, Chart.js, MySQL, Sequelize, NodeJS, Express.js, bcrypt.js, dotenv, multer
- **Type:** Full Stack

### Google Book | https://github.com/Yunusib12/rg-books.git | https://reactgbook.herokuapp.com/

- A Single Page Application query and display books based on user searches
- A full MERN stack application allows users to save books to a database to refer to later.
- Tools used: Bootstrap, Express, Node.js, React, MongoDB, Heroku, Socket.io
- Type: Full Stack

#### EXPERIENCE

## Technology Specialist Portland Adult Education

2020 - Now

Portland,

Maine

Design and manage a system to support the distribution and collection of over 400 loaner devices for students including: laptops, tablets, Chromebooks and smartphones.

Key Accomplishments:

- Build and maintain the student loaner device system
- Implemented an automated notification system that send notification based on student attendance

## Junior Software Developer Pierce Promotion

2016 - 2018

Portland.

Maine

Design, develop, and unit test applications in accordance with established standards, implemented web applications using Visual Basic.Net. Participated in peer-reviews of solution designs and related code. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- Re-designed most their application to be responsive
- Helped implement box file upload in their applications

## Web Designer/ Computer Lab Assistant Portland Adult Education

2015 - 2016

Portland,

Maine

Design, develop, and implemented their web site.

Key Accomplishments:

- Design and implement website for NMRC (www.nmrcmaine.org)
- Assist 250 students speaking more than 7 languages using different English learning websites

# Assistant Technical Director Spidernet SA (Internet Service Provider)

2012 - 2015

Bujumbura, Burundi

Ensured virtual connectivity between ISP and Backbone (MTN Rwanda) Monitored and trouble-shot connectivity issues between ISP and more than 1,000 clients. Key Accomplishments:

- Managed, configured, and troubleshot VM, Webmail, DNS, Cacti and VoIP Servers
- Supervised and coordinated 30 technicians in absence of technical director
- Used PHP, JavaScript, MySQL to develop a web application that monitored antenna, switch, router and servers and kept track of all field installation and workload.

## Web Designer & Network Administrator Afriregister

2007 - 2011

Bujumbura, Burundi

Provided support for IT hardware, software and networks for 150 hosted website and domain names. Managed, configured, and troubleshot Linux servers and operating systems including: Centos, Fedora, Debian and Ubuntu.

## Web Design / IT Specialist Burundi Youth Training Center

2004 - 2006

Bujumbura, Burundi

Updated website, using JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL and managed IT system security for computer lab.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Amazon Web Service: Southern Maine Community College

October 2020 - December 2020

- A 9-week technical program focused on building and validating the overall understanding of the AWS Cloud service skills on s3 bucket, DynamoDB, Lambda function, API Gateway, EC2, IAM, SNS

### Coding Bootcamp Certificate: University of New Hampshire June 2019 - December 2019

- A 24-week intensive technical program focused on developing skills in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ¡Query, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express and React.js

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Sciences: University of Kinshasa, Republic Democratic of Congo 2011

#### Additional Information

- Over 5 years of experience in software development including system analysis, software design, project management, coding, testing, delivery, and maintenance.
- Aptitude for analyzing, debugging code, identifying problems, and creating solutions.
- Capable of rapidly learning new technologies and successfully applying them to projects.
- Energetic and self-motivated team player.
- Capable of working in a dynamic, fast-paced environment and manage multiple tasks to completion.
- Strong verbal and written communication skills that convey clarity.

#### Technical Skills

- Programming languages: Asp.Net (MVC 5, Web forms, Web Services), PHP, VB, VB.Net JavaScript, Google Apps Scripts.
- Markup languages: HTML, CSS, XML
- Frameworks and Libraries: .NET, Bootstrap, React, AJAX, ¡Query, JSON, Angular.
- API: RESTful (JSON)
- Code Versioning: Git & GitHub
- Design patterns: SOLID principles, Gang of four
- Relational Databases: MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server 2016, MS Access, Data modeling
- . No SQL Databases: MongoDB
- Content Management systems: WordPress, Joomla, Spip
- Operating systems: Windows XP2&3, Vista, 7,8,10, Linux
- Cloud technologies: Amazon Web Services (AWS), S3 Bucket, Azure, Vagrant, Docker
- Development Environments: Dreamweaver, Visual studio, Notepad++, Sublime
- Graphics: Adobe creative suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Image ready, PageMaker, Audition, Premier)
- Office: Microsoft office package (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Publisher, Access)
- Object Oriented Programing
- Google Apps Script (Apps Script API, Clasp)